this video is about yaml document
streams you're like what's a yaml
document stream this is a yaml document
stream all right right here we have we
have multiple yaml documents and you
generally can identify them from their
triple dots and it gets kind of
interesting down here but I want you to
pay close attention to this and I'm
making this video
because this is very frequently
misunderstood and there are so many
applications that are parsing yaml
totally incorrectly by thinking they
understand yaml if you are not parsing
yaml using a standard library and even
then those libraries are broken I'm
going to show you that there's a place
down here where this one is actually
broken the yl be3 pars of foro is
totally broken but that's the best
you're going to get if you try to do
this with regular expressions or
something you will fail and let me tell
you why because this is a totally valid
yaml document stream so let's do this
everybody in the chat where are the
documents where is the beginning and
where does the document
end okay so there's 1 2 3 4 5 six
there's six documents in
here where do they start and end
if you said that the first document
starts right after here after the
document separator you'd be
wrong the first document starts right
here and it goes all the way through to
here wrong
here that's the first
document and there is no marker for the
end of the document including triple do
triple dot if you know what that is that
does not that does not indicate the end
of a yaml document
the official specification says that the
beginning of another document in a
document stream is something that begins
with this
or another document
identifier so the next document is
here including the document which comes
on the second line so basically you know
how many times you know how many times
I've seen people assume that the triple
Dash is the beginning of a document and
they just do a flat shell parse of the
whole thing that that's wrong why
because if you split this file based on
the triple do dashes you're going to
leave metadata for the upcoming document
behind in the previous
buffer so it's wrong splitting this file
into things that have triple dashes is
wrong you how many times I see people
all the time all the time people do that
so so here you go this is the next do
doent where's the next one right here
that's right you can set up your tags
these tags provide metadata that that
allow some of the more complex things in
y most people don't ever use doesn't
matter that is how the specification is
written you want to do it right that's
how you do it yeah and what what the
hell's going on with these comments down
here right what are they associated with
this first thing here we'll talk about
that another time that is the next
document okay here's one that's going to
blow people away remember how how many
people are splitting they're splitting
on the triple dot because they think
that there's just whites space at the
end
wrong wrong wrong wrong wrong wrong so
wrong you can have the D the document
the beginning of a document is three
dashes and a
space period you can put anything after
here and you can immediately start a
document you can put a map value here if
you wanted to
that is valid yaml so if you are
splitting the file based on Triple do
triple Dash and you are and you are
expecting there to be nothing after that
because that's how you've seen it and
everything that's ever been producing y
you're doing it
wrong and and I I'm very sorry to have
to tell you that here's another case
here's a case where the value begins on
the second line but the tag is on the
same line as the triple Dash
and this is an example of one that's
actually broken this is an example of
one which you'll have to watch the other
video but what this says is we've
declared this is supposed to see this as
a single string as if I had written it
something like this if I had written it
sort of like this right by putting the
the the bang bang St up here as the tag
tag definition this is by specification
super supposed to be interpreted as a
single string and it is not interpreted
as a single string by the yaml V3
Library created by canonical and now
which is now the the final Authority in
yaml for it's built into everything
kubernetes everything so so that is I'm
going to prove I'll show you how that's
not a thing here's another one so this
is what is this this is a valid yamal
document containing What containing a
sequence
right 1 two three and we're not we're
not even going to get into the regular
things people complain about when they
do yaml they complain about false and
true and all that stuff which are
interpreted differently by pretty much
every single parser out
there so hopefully this will give you a
heads up because if you're going to go
through and you're going to parse the
AML data and you're going to split it
number one don't split based on Triple
Dash don't do it two know that stuff
that begins with percent goes with the
docu the proceeding document that's the
beginning that is the true beginning
that's the med the beginning of a
document and it does exist three you
know that the Y be three parts is
probably pretty broken and where you can
put you know stuff on the same line so
these are things if you if you actually
yaml yaml is a disaster okay it's the
best disaster that we have right now and
actually I I know people who know people
who igny who and others who created yaml
I'm not ungrateful I just feel like you
know it's one of these over engineered
things really smart people do they they
make they have a good idea and then they
throw a bunch of other in there
that doesn't
belong you know if it if they had made
it compatible with Json and people have
been fighting about it doesn't matter
the yaml overlords have decided that is
what we're going to use for everything
so you better parse it properly and by
the way the only way to parse it
properly is to do a recursive dentry
parser by writing Yeah by writing
something like a closure that that's in
a that operates on by walking the the
node tree the node. yaml uh uh type
which I guarantee you 90% of the people
watching this video have never heard of
yl. node and that is the most important
thing you could discover this year in
terms of yaml because once you know
about it you can Marshall to and from it
and you have exact direct control over
all of the types that are pars from the
m willb 3 parser and that's in a
different video so that's all for now